我真傻 真的
I have been a fool.
我犯过错误 大错特错
Made mistakes. Monumental ones.
现在我明白了 我永远都不会成为一名领袖
I now realize that I was never destined to be  a leader
更不用说和他平起平坐
or even an equal partner.
不过 我现在已经尘埃落定
And, I'm at peace with that.
我已经认清了自己在宇宙中的位置
I have gained a clear understanding of my place in this universe
认清了自我 那个自始至终的我
of who I am, of who I was always meant to be.
红蜘蛛 副指挥官
Starscream, second-in-command
威震天陛下的心腹侍从
humble servant to Lord Megatron.
谢谢你的聆听 声波
Thank you for listening, Soundwave.
这是真的吗？
Is this true?
红蜘蛛从没说起过吗？
Starscream never mentioned it?
如果他又想故技重施
If he's up to his old tricks
我一定把他捏成碎屑
I shall grind him into powder.
红蜘蛛？
Starscream?
威震天陛下 请原谅毒蜘蛛的无礼取闹
Lord Megatron, please excuse Airachnid's impertinence.
好了 我忘了告诉您什么鬼东西吗？
Now, what was it that I allegedly failed to mention?
先驱号
The Harbinger.
怎么了?
What about it?
许多年前 一艘霸天虎运输船在这个星球坠毁
Eons ago a Decepticon transport crash-landed on this planet.
噢 拜托 这谁都知道
Oh, please, common knowledge.
刚到地球时 我就去查看了坠机地点
I scouted the crash site when we first arrived on Earth.
那么我猜 你一定已经收回了 先驱号运载的武器原型吧？
Then I presume you recovered the experimental weapon prototype the Harbinger had been transporting?
坠机地点在哪儿？
Where is the crash site?
地点并没有录入飞船的数据库
It was never logged into your ship's database.
你没有记录霸天虎运输船的坐标？
You failed to record the coordinates of a Decepticon transport?
是我疏忽 主人
An oversight, master.
但确切位置就在我脑子里
But I noted its exact location.
那你就带毒蜘蛛过去
Then you can lead Airachnid there.
让她把那件武器原型给我带回来
So that she may retrieve the prototype for me.
我有私人本地导游了
My personal native guide.
真高兴
How delightful.
嘿 搭档
Hey, partner
你这里风景不错嘛
heck of a view you got up here.
但愿你的火种还能听到我说话 其实…
If there's even a small chance your spark is out there listening, well...
我们真的需要你 小飞
we could really use you, Cliff.
最近几乎每天都有新的霸天虎冒出来
Seems like every day another Decepticon arrives on the scene.
我们人手不够 火力不足
We are outnumbered and outgunned.
算了 我知道你会说
Yea, I know what you'd say.
“看来要好好打一仗了”
'Sounds like a fair fight.'
如果我们注定生活在这样的世界 那无所谓
And if that's the world we live in, so be it.
我只想让你知道
I just want you to know:
我没有放弃
I haven't given up.
我要把杀死你的虎子揪出来
I'm going to find the Con who took you from us.
你的机械形态缺乏冲刺的快感
Your chosen vehicle mode lacks thrust.
你是来领路的 还是来显摆的？
Are you going to preen or are you going to guide?
我会告诉你先驱号的准确位置
I will reveal the exact location of the Harbinger
可你得说清楚 我们在找什么
when you tell me exactly what we are looking for.
到时候自然真相大白
That information is need-to-know.
现在嘛 你不必知道
And right now, you don't.
噢 你最好放尊重一点 毒蜘蛛
Oh, You would do well to respect me, Airachnid.
在投靠威震天之前
Before I joined Megatron
我可是能量追踪者中队的空军指挥官
I was Air Commander of a squadron of Energon Seekers.
那是在塞博特恩 离现在有些年头了吧？
On Cybertron, and how many eons ago was that?
就在最近
Just recently
我一个人干掉了擎天柱的得力干将之一 飞过山
I personally vanquished one of Optimus Prime's fiercest warriors--Cliff Jumper.
你干掉了一个汽车人？
You snuffed an Autobot?
是的 没错 丝毫没有手软
Yes I did. Without mercy.
噢 威震天本想在矿井里把你干掉 可他也一时心软
Oh, even Megatron showed you mercy when he planned to terminate you at the mine.
什么？他连这都告诉你了？
What? He told you about that?
聊天而已
We talk.
飞船残骸就在我们所在位置的正下方
The wreckage lies just beneath where we stand.
我得去找个入口
I will need to find a point of entry.
真能显摆
Show off.
随便你吧 多年前我就已经把这里翻遍了
Suit yourself, I conducted a thorough search of this husk years ago.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
访问货物清单
Accessing the cargo manifest
你在翻遍这里的时候 没想过这么做吗？
or didn't you think to do that during your thorough search?
笨蛋 飞船的系统几个世纪以来都没有激活
Idiot. The ship's systems haven't been activated for eons.
汽车人会探测到它的能量特征
The Autobots could detect its energy signature.
啊 找到了 在23区
Ah, here it is. Section 23.
擎天柱 我们侦测到一个霸天虎的能量特征
Optimus, our scanners have detected a Decepticon energy profile
但是种…古老的信号
but it's... ancient.
历史总是可以和当代接轨 救护车
The past has a way of catching up with the present, Ratchet.
23区应该就在…这儿
Section 23 should be right about... here.
飞船到头了
The ship just ends.
它一定是在坠落时断成了两截
It must have broken in half during the crash.
也许在空中已经断了
Or in the air.
如果你真的做过研究
If you performed actual research
不会不知道 先驱号是被汽车人部队从天上打下来的
You would have learned that an Autobot battalion shot the Harbinger out of the sky.
另一半飞船离这儿多远？
How far away is the other half?
应该说 到时候自然真相大白
I'm afraid that information is needed-to-know.
你要…
What are you...
你想让我在威震天面前出丑吗？
You're trying to make me look like a fool before Megatron.
让我空手而归 而你去独吞那个武器
Have me return empty handed while you locate that weapon yourself.
你竟敢指责我！
How dare you acuse me!
你不过是个食腐动物 喜欢投机取巧！
You are nothing but a scavenger, an opportunist.
你不也是这种人吗？
Aren't you one to talk?
也许吧 但我已经洗心革面了
Perhaps, but I've changed
从前我曾经走错过路
seeing the error of my ways.
但我现在活着的目的 就为威震天效劳
I live to serve Megatron now.
你休想活命 除非你告诉我另一半飞船在哪儿 快说！
You won't live to serve anyone if you don't tell me where to find the rest of the ship, now.
向北走几公里 穿过一道石拱门
A few kliks north of here through a stone arch.
快把我放开！
Now release me!
我拿到武器后 就放了你
When I have the weapon in hand.
不过 但愿在没人带路的情况下 我能找回来
That is, if I can find my way back without my guide.
这可不好玩儿 毒蜘蛛
This is not funny, Airachnid
马上回来给我松绑
come back here right now and cut me lose.
毒蜘蛛 这是命令！
Airachnid, that is an order!
我是你的指挥官！
I am your commanding officer!
毒蜘蛛
Airachnid.
投降吧
Surrender.
毒蜘蛛 你这个叛徒！
Airachnid, you traitor!
阿尔茜 等等！
Arcee, wait!
阿尔茜
Arcee.
我没想到 你会重新投奔霸天虎
I didn't peg you for resigning with the Decepticons.
缓兵之计罢了 阿尔茜
A temporary arrangement, Arcee.
你知道 我更喜欢单干
You know I prefer working alone.
话说 想在成长日志里 再加上几个阵亡战友的名字吗？
Speaking of add anymore deceased partners to your growing list?
毒蜘蛛 放开她
Airachnid, release her.
阿尔茜 你应该知道 不能独自和敌人交战
Arcee, you know better than to engage the enemy alone.
她是例外 她把挡板害惨了
Not her. Not after what she did to Tailgate.
不 求你了 挡板！
No, please. Tailgate!
她必须付出代价
She will pay.
复仇并不能让牺牲的战士回来
Revenge will not bring back those we have lost.
明白吗？
Is that understood?
快走
Move it.
用不着动粗吧
No need to use force.
你们想知道什么 我全说
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
呵呵 真的吗？
Hehe, is that right?
你想要什么回报？
And what you want in return?
我想要…加入你们
I want to be on your side.
加入我们？哈哈 你要是能当汽车人
On our side? Haha, yeah, right.
我还能跟堕落金刚玩抛球呢！
And I've been lobbing with the Fallen!
你不会背叛霸天虎的
You wouldn't betray the Decepticons.
为什么不会？
Wouldn't I?
他们最近都是怎么待我的
What have they done for me lately
除了羞辱我
besides humiliate me
监视我 还降我的级
spy on me, demote me?
威震天不念旧情 想把我干掉
Megatron tried to extinguish my spark in cold blood
还有那个一心想取代我的混蛋毒蜘蛛
then all but to replace me with that treacherous wretch Airachnid.
她竟然丢下我不管！
She abandoned me!
让我自生自灭！
Left me for scrap!
所以 干嘛不过河拆桥呢？
So why not rat them out?
他说的是实话 威震天的确想杀了他
He is telling the truth about Megatron trying to scrap him.
是我亲眼看见的
I saw with my own eyes.
你不是想说 你相信红蜘蛛吧？
You're not saying you actually trust Starscream?
相信他？绝不会
Trust him? Never.
但这次我们也许能联手对敌
But this may be the one time our objective's alined.
你的担心很有道理 隔板
You're right to be wary, Bulkhead.
但我赞成阿尔茜
But I agree with Arcee.
我简直按捺不住火种的狂跳
Be still, my beating spark.
你猜怎么着
What do you know.
可能又是个陷阱
Could still be a trap.
红蜘蛛在威震天面前一直三心二意
Starscream's loyalty to Megatron has always been questionable.
如果他真的和霸天虎决裂
If he has truly split from the Decepticons
这个了解军情的俘虏 也许是个值得结交的盟友
our prisoner's knowledge of their agendas could make him a valuable ally.
你不是认真的吧？
You don't mean permanently?
难道要把基地的钥匙也交给他吗？
As in key to the base and everything?
尽管有些不切实际
However unlikely that scenario
但每个生命体都应该得到赎罪的机会
every sentient being deserves an opportunity for redemption.
即使他是汽车人杀手吗？那毒蜘蛛呢？
Even Bot-killers? Even Airachnid?
如果不抱这个希望 我们可能永远得不到长治久安
Without that hope, we may never achieve lasting peace.
太阳晒屁股了 蜘蛛侠
Rise and shine, Screamy.
我们到了 飞船在哪里？
We are here. Where is the ship?
穿过石拱门 在石堆中间
It's through the arch, among the stones.
隔板 大黄蜂 跟我来
Bulkhead, Bumblebee, you are with me.
阿尔茜 留下看管战俘
Arcee, remain with our prisoner.
擎天柱 求你了
Optimus, please.
为了挡板
For Tailgate.
你渴望为挡板复仇 只会一再影响你的判断力
Your desire to avenge Tailgate will only continue to cloud your judgement.
真的有必要用手铐吗？
Is the clamp really necessary?
我保证不飞走
I promise not to fly away.
我都要抽筋了
It's really giving me a crick.
我把你扔回车箱里如何
I can shove you back in the trailer.
保持警惕
Be alert.
毒蜘蛛善于从地下攻击
Airachnid is known to attack from below ground.
明白
Right.
让我来
I got it.
静止器 果然名不虚传
The Immobilizer. True to its name.
我并没有那么坏 你知道
I'm not really so bad, you know.
威震天才是十恶不赦的坏人
Megatron, he is the evil one.
跟那些想听的人说去吧
Tell it to someone who cares.
跟谁说？毒蜘蛛？
Like whom? Airachnid?
我无时无刻不想掐住她该死的脖子
What I wouldn't do to get my hands around her wretched throat.
这一点 我们倒可以达成一致
So we can agree on one thing.
噢 你根本想不到
Oh, you have no idea.
她莫名其妙地出现
She showed up one day
然后呢 她就像个大管家一样
and the next thing you know, she is acting like she runs the place.
她对威震天吹枕边风
She whispered lies into Megatron's ear
而且还坐上了本座的交椅！
maneuvered to rob me of my rightful place.
是啊 她还杀了我的搭档
Well, she terminated my partner.
什么？！她把杀掉他的功劳安在自己头上？！
What?! She is taking credit for scrapping him now, too?!
那是我干的！
That was my doing!
什么？
What?
你当时不在场
You weren't there.
啊 我当然不在
Ah, of course I wasn't.
我不知道刚才在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
你说的是谁？
Who are you talking about?
谁也没说 你说的是谁？
No one, who are you talking about?
挡板
Tailgate.
谁是挡板？
Who's Tailgate?
原来是你
You were the one.
是你杀了飞过山
You extinguished Cliffjumper.
飞过山？
Cliffjumper?
不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
你搞错了
You misunderstand.
不是你想的那样
It wasn't like you think.
机械兵打得他半死不活
The Troopers mortally wounded him.
我是想帮助飞过山…
I was trying to help Cliffjumper...
帮他结束痛苦
put him out of his misery.
是他求我的！
He begged me to!
好吧 好吧！这是个失误！
OK, OK! it was a mistake!
我曾经犯过错误 但我已经改了！
I've made many, but I've changed!
你不会杀害一个手无寸铁的俘虏 对吧？
You wouldn't terminate a defenceless prisoner, would you?
什么…那是什么？
What... what is that?
你手铐的钥匙
The key to your cuffs.
为什么？
What for?
换成小飞 他会给你一个决斗的机会
Cliff would have given you a fighting chance.
不 求你 我不想决斗！
No. Please, I... I don't want to!
过去的都过去了
What's past is past.
现在我是你们的一员！
I'm one of you now!
不 不 不…
No, no, no, no...
把它捡起来！
Take it!
胆小鬼
You're pathetic.
有问题吗 阿尔茜？
Something wrong, Arcee?
我还以为你想决斗呢
I thought you wanted a fight.
不许动
Freeze.
你比你的前搭档棘手一点
You are tougher to scrap than your former partner
至少比我杀掉的那个强
at least the one I scrapped.
挡板也像飞过山一样不堪一击吗？
Was Tailgate weak like Cliffjumper?
有种就接着说 红蜘蛛
Just keep talking, Starscream.
告诉我 虫子
Tell me, bug.
你认为 威震天会喜欢他的新战利品吗？
Do you think Megatron will enjoy his new trophies?
他也许会用这个大块头来当靶子
He'll probably use the bulky one here for target practice.
擎天柱啊 真是物有所值
Prime is the true prize.
也许可以用他来装饰威震天战舰的船首
Perhaps he'll adorn the prow of Megatron's warship.
至于你 虫子
But you, bug.
我怀疑 威震天只会把你当废铁拆掉
I suspect Meagtron will simply dismantle you for spare parts.
作为一个游侠 一只食腐动物
As a rogue, a scavenger
我应该带着这个宝贝消失在夜色里
I should disappear into the night with this treasure.
但是 用它来取悦威震天 是个不容错过的大好机会
But using it to warm my way into Megatron's favor is too good an opportunity to pass up.
你说是不是 擎天柱？
Wouldn't you say, Prime?
有了这样的战绩
I mean with results like this.
我可以成为威震天的心腹
I could earn Megatron's eternal trust.
你这个白痴！
You fool!
你应该趁我不能还手的时候杀了我
You should have finished me when I was hopeless to fight.
就像我杀死飞过山一样
Just like I finished Cliffjumper.
现在 准备和你的那些搭档团聚吧
Now, prepare to reunite with your partners.
说什么？我听不见你的遗言
What's that? I can't hear your last words.
这…是…为了…飞过山！
This is for Cliffjumper!
来吧 动手吧！
Go on. Do it!
如果回到霸天虎那里 威震天只会当我谋反 把我杀掉
Megatron will only terminate me for treason if I dare return to the Decepticons.
你可以成为那个 帮我结束痛苦的人
You may as well be the one to put me out of my misery.
你以为我需要怂恿吗？
As if I needed convincing.
什么？等等！不！
What? Wait! No!
你让红蜘蛛落在汽车人手里？！
You left Starscream with the Autobots?!
你知不知道 你的愚蠢失误会带来什么后果？！
Do you have any notion of the consequences of your blunder?!
但是 阁下！
But, my lordship!
丢掉了静止器 全怪红蜘蛛无能！
It was Starscream's incompetence that cost us the Immobilizer!
我才不在乎那个小玩意儿！
I don't care about some trinket!
我的副官成了敌人的阶下囚！
My second-in-command is a prisoner of the enemy!
这就是说 霸天虎的所有情报 可能已经落入了汽车人的手里！
Which means all Decepticon intelligence could be at the fingertips of the Autobots!
破损情况很严重
The damage look bad
但很容易就修好了
but it was a snap to repair
可以把对你们的效用逆转
allowing us to reverse its effect on you.
你们应该很快就能行动自如了
You should regain your full range of motion before long.
那阿尔茜呢？
And Arcee?
作为一辆两轮车 她恢复得够快了
She is rather resilient for a two-wheeler.
痊愈的只是那些皮外伤
It is the external wounds which heal the quickest.
我以为 拼命杀敌会让我忘掉过去
I thought settling scores would allow me to move on...
但是 我却把早日结束战争的希望赶跑了
Instead, I chased away our hope of winning this war anytime soon.
智慧并不是天生的 阿尔茜
Wisdom cannot be granted, Arcee.
必须靠拼搏得来 有时要付出代价
It must be earned, sometimes at a cost.
我真傻 真的
I have been a fool.
我犯过错误
Made mistakes.
大错特错
Monumental ones.
但是 我已经认清了自己在宇宙中的位置
But I have gained a clear understanding of my place in this universe.
认清了自我
Of who I am.
红蜘蛛
Starscream: aligned with no side
不效忠任何人
servant, to no one.